Mitchell Marino

Full Stack Software Engineer

San Pedro, CA | (310) 991-6782

Email | GitHub | Portfolio | LinkedIn

Summary Statement

A highly motivated software engineer with one year of experience specializing in JavaScript, Python, and application development. Seeking to utilize a unique educational and professional background with strong analytical and problem-solving skills to thrive and grow as a full stack software engineer.

Skills

- JavaScript, Python, Ruby, Godot, HTML/CSS, SQL(Postgres), NoSQL(MongoDB)
- Git, Github, Bitbucket/Jira, REST APIs, AWS
- Microsoft Office, Visual Studio, Figma

Experience

Software Engineer | Roadies Labs | Remote | October 2022 - Present

- Contributed to entire development, release, and updates of Roadies Labs website, built on MERN stack.
- Collaborated with the design team to plan and implement responsive user interfaces and new features using React, HTML, and CSS.
- Developed backend REST API in Node/Express to deliver user and website data, along with payment and blockchain token integration.
- Integrated unit and integration tests with Jest and React Testing Library, reducing debugging time significantly.
- Worked on CI/CD pipeline to efficiently and safely deliver updated versions of software to AWS.

Software Engineering Immersive | General Assembly | Remote | April – July 2022

- Successfully completed 420 hours of expert-led instruction in HTML, CSS3, Javascript, and Python, and applied those skills by building applications.
- Learned and practiced application development lifecycle using agile and scrum methodology.
- Applied computer science principles in Algorithms, Data Structures, and Design Patterns.
- Built 4 capstone projects to solidify full-stack software development technologies and principles:
 - -Stratego: Board game built with HTML5, Canvas, CSS, and JavaScript [GitHub Repository]
 - -Simplifry: Recipe storage app built with Node/Express [GitHub Repository]
 - -Checkmate: Organization goal completion app built on MERN stack [GitHub Repository]
 - -Flex: Workout scheduling app built with Django, Pytest, and SQL. [GitHub Repository]

Research Technician | Zymo Research | Irvine, CA | August 2020 – December 2021

- Performed RNA extraction and RT-qPCR of over 25,000 clinical samples to diagnose COVID-19 infection.
- Managed the product development, marketing, and launch of "ZymoScript" RT / RT-qPCR products.
- Provided technical support for 10 customers per week by assisting with experimental design and/or product troubleshooting.

Education

General Assembly | Software Engineering Immersive | Remote | 2022

University of California, Los Angeles | Los Angeles, CA | 2016 – 2020

Bachelor of Science in Molecular, Cell, and Developmental Biology

- Cumulative GPA: 3.61
- Dean's Honors List 3 quarters